[
  {
    "_id": "q1",
    "question": "What is the importance of form?",
    "answer": "A form is important because it allows user input data to be collected."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q2",
    "question": "How many input types do you know?",
    "answer": "Just enough, for now."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q3",
    "question": "Mention at least four attributes of an input element",
    "answer": "Below are attributes that's been used in the past so far",
    "list": [
      "name",
      "type",
      "value",
      "size",
      "min",
      "max",
      "required",
      "placeholder",
      "checked"
    ],
    "footnote": [
      "More reading: [MDN](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/input)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q4",
    "question": "What is the importance of htmlFor?",
    "answer": "Since \"for\" is a reserved keyword in Javascript, htmlFor is used in its place."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q5",
    "question": "Write an input type which is not given in the example if there is?",
    "answer": "Below are some input type listed but not used in the last example",
    "list": [
      "range",
      "password",
      "url",
      "image",
      "hidden",
      "datetime-local",
      "month",
      "week",
      "time",
      "reset",
      "search",
      "submit",
      "button"
    ],
    "footnote": [
      "More reading: [MDN](https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/input)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q6",
    "question": "What is a controlled input?",
    "answer": "A controlled input is the use of a callback like onChange to update its value."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q7",
    "question": "What do you need to write a controlled input?",
    "answer": "A controlled input is needed to update its value. If not done, the input will return to the original its original state/value after render."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q8",
    "question": "What event type do you use to listen changes on an input field?",
    "answer": "onChange"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q9",
    "question": "What is the value of a checked checkbox?",
    "answer": "true"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q10",
    "question": "When do you use onChange, onBlur, onSubmit?",
    "answer": "",
    "list": [
      "onChange is used to track the value of an input whenever there is any kind of change in it.",
      "onBlur is used to track the change in an input only after losing focus. In the example given, it was used to initiate validation.",
      "onSubmit is used, in the example, to prevent the default action of a form. If not prevented, the page will re-render, clear the form, and initiate the specified action (HTML inline) on the form, if any."
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q11",
    "question": "What is the purpose of writing e.preventDefault() inside the submit handler method?",
    "answer": "e.preventDefault() is used to stop the default action on forms which includes re-rendering of the page."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q12",
    "question": "How do you bind data in React? The first input field example is data binding in React.",
    "answer": "Data binding in React is using onChange in a controlled input to store and update it in a state variable."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q13",
    "question": "What is validation?",
    "answer": "Validation is a process to ensure that data entered is valid, follows the desired format and to prevent malicious users or data."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q14",
    "question": "What is the event type you use to listen when an input changes?",
    "answer": "onChange"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q15",
    "question": "What are event types you use to validate an input?",
    "answer": "Below are the event types used to validate input",
    "list": [
      "onBlur",
      "onChange",
      "onSubmit"
    ]
  }
]